BLOSSOM EZE

blossomeze@vahoo.com | https://github.com/blossomeze | https://twitter.com/blossomeze

SUMMARY

From Nigeria to the digital realm, I am a passionate Frontend Web Developer with an eye for code aesthetics, crafting visually captivating interfaces pixel by pixel. I combine my love for beautiful UI design with dedication to clean code and application of best practices to deliver solid results with the best user experience and a codebase that is scalable and maintainable.

EXPERIENCES

WALKERS DAO - Onsite

Web Developer

April 2023 - Present

- Responsible for designing and developing responsive websites and web applications.
- Implemented clean and maintainable codes using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.
- Collaborated with designers and other developers to create visually appealing and functional user interfaces.
- Maintained cross-browser compatibility and optimized website performance.
- Integrated data from APIs and databases into web applications.
- Conducted testing and debugging to identify and resolve issues.

BRIDGING GAPS SCHOOL - Onsite

Information Technology Staff

Sept 2022 - Nov 2022

- Troubleshooted and resolved problems related to computer systems, network connectivity and software applications.
- Responded to IT-related emergencies and resolved issues promptly to minimize disruptions to the learning environment.
- Implemented and enforced IT policies and procedures to ensure the responsible use of technology resources.
- Provided excellent customer service and communication to address the IT needs of students and staff

IRENT - Onsite

Frontend Developer

July 2022 - August 2023

- Designed and developed responsive and visually engaging user interfaces for the company's website.
- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript to code and maintain website features and functionalities ensuring a smooth and intuitive user experience.
- Optimized web assets for performance and responsiveness to improve website loading times and enhance user engagement.
- Integrated third-party APIs and tools to enhance website functionality and user interactions.
- Conducted regular testing and debugging to identify and resolve frontend issues, ensuring high-quality deliverables.
- Implemented version control systems (eg. Git) to track code changes and facilitate seamless collaboration within the development team.
- Leveraged technical expertise to enhance the company's online presence and deliver user-centric solutions.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

VIRTUAL ASSISTANT

July 2022 - March 2023

- Responded to customer emails, forwarded important messages and ensured timely communication.
- Set up meetings, calls, and appointments on the executives calendar and sent meeting reminders.
- Answered phone calls, responded to messages and redirected calls to the executives as needed.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - University of Uyo

December 2019 - Present

Frontend Engineering Intern - ALX Africa

March 2023 - Present

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- React JS
- Tailwind CSS
- Material UI
- Redux
- Node JS
- Git
- C
- BootStrap

SOFT SKILLS

- 2+ years experience in verbal and written communications
- Good customer service and interpersonal skills
- Sound judgment and problem-solving skills